

EXPERIENCES CERTIFICATES GIVEN LECTURES EDUCATION INTERESTS

REFERENCES

SERCAN ÇELENK [EXPERT SOFTWARE ENGINEER]

ISTANBUL / TURKEY · [+90 530 200 85 02] · SERCANCELENK@GMAIL.COM

"Passionate about IT Profession and Computer Engineering. Have years of experience on Software Development. Designed and building several Softwares with Java, Scala, Ruby, Python. Both had experience in Startups and Enterprise Scale organizations.."









EXPERT SOFTWARE ENGINEER

EXPERIENCE

TRENDYOL TECH

01/2021 - Present

Seamless e-commerce experience to our customers and vendors, Seller Experience Technologies

TURKCELL TECHNOLOGY

EXPERT SOFTWARE ENGINEER

04/2016 - 12/2020

 ONLINE GAMING PLATFORM Core backend development

Fizy Music Platform, Magazine Platform, Online Gaming Platform, TV+ Middleware

• Reactive Programming with Java 1.8 and projectreactor.io. o Reactive Manifesto, Monads, Functional Programming

- o Reactive Apache Kafka Cluster Pub/Sub Messaging and Reactive Websocket
- 250000+ connections in one machine on T instant o Reactive Redis Template, Google Guava Memoizer for in-memory cache
- Spring 5 Webflux
- FIZY MUSIC PLATFORM Online Music Streaming Platform

Core Development Spring Cloud Netflix Microservice Architecture, Spring Boot 2.x, Java 1.8

- Functional Redis Cluster, Redis Sentinel
- Consul Service Registry, Ribbon, Zuul Filter Java Concurrency for music content data polling
- MAGAZINE PLATFORM o Online Magazine Platform

• Replatform Project from .NET to Java Microservice

Dockerize modules, Openshift, Jenkins integration

o Dockerize modules, Openshift, Jenkins integration

Spring Cloud Netflix Microservice Architecture, Spring Boot 2.x, Java 1.8 **Functional**

- TV+ CHAT MODULE
 - o Reactive Apache Kafka Messaging, Reactive Websocket, Reactive Redis, Spring 5.x, Reactive Programming Spring 5 Webflux

Hazelcast Multicast Distributed Cache

Consul Service Registry, Ribbon, Zuul Filter

Websocket, Reactive Redis, Spring 5.x, Reactive Programming Spring 5 Webflux

Mockito JUnit

Spring Boot 1.5, Microservice Architecture, ELK, Zepplin, Zuul Filter, Mockito

• Reactive Apache Kafka Messaging for realtime match details, Reactive

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

DUMETECH

Mockito JUnit

GOLLER CEPTE MIDDLEWARE

Project based working in Payment Team. PAYMENT MODULE

GLOBAL CAPITAL GROUP ONLINE BANKING COMPANY

10/2015 - 04/2016

01/2015 - 01/2016

10/2013 - 01/2015

04/2012 - 11/2013

04/2008 - 05/2010

Turkcell Technology

09/2003 - 09/2008

Dumetech

JUnit

International Hackhaton in Istanbul. MESAJ.NINJA - CLOUD MESSAGING APPLICATION VIA WHATSAPP, VIBER

Dumetech is startup company of us. We developed Mesaj. Ninja Project that online

messaging platform via Whatsapp, Viber, Bip. Also we acquire reward from BNP Pariba

HEAD OF CORE DEVELOPMENT(OUR STARTUP COMPANY)

• TEB BNP Paribas Hackathon Winner Project

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

EG SOFTWARE COMPANY

AngularJs

o Spring Technologies, Java 1.8, Java concurrency, Ruby Cucumber Integration,

TURKCELL TECHNOLOGY Eclipse Plugin and Middleware development for Release Management in Turkcell.

 DEVELOPER OF SDLC FOR CI / CD AND RELEASE MANAGEMENT PROCESSES o Java 1.7, Spring Data, J2EE, Eclipse Plugin Development, Rest Api

Main Banking Team, development of financial applications.

Spring boot 1.5, Java 1.8, Spring Data, Mysql DB

o Dockerize modules, Openshift, Jenkins integration

FLEXDQ - DATA QUALITY TOOL FOR INTEGRATED SYSTEMS

Spring Quartz Dynamic Job Scheduling

Hazelcast Multicast Distributed Cache

- o Developed the following modules: Web Api, Schedule Api, Rest Api, Log monitoring Api • Integration of Clearcase and SVN • Eclipse Plugin Development, SWT adapted, Threaded GUI
- **AKBANK TECHNOLOGY**

05/2010 - 04/2012 **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER MAG SOFTWARE COMPANY

Startup Company, Developed Government Applications and R&D Projects.

Startup Company, Developed Government Applications and R&D Projects.

✓ TEB BNP Paribas Hackathon Winner Project ✓ Spring Technologies, Java 1.8, Java concurrency, Ruby Cucumber Integration, AngularJs

indexing and grouping news

VIBER

PROJECTS

HAZZMON-IO

✓ Hazelcast Key and Cluster Management Tool

✓ Github: https://github.com/sercancelenk/hazzmon-io

✓ Manage your hazelcast on-demand for your project. Easy setup.

✓ Spring Boot 2.x, Hazelcast Supported All Versions, AngularJs 6 for UI

MESAJ.NINJA - CLOUD MESSAGING APPLICATION VIA WHATSAPP,

Personal **GUNDEM.IN INTELLIGENCE NEWS CRAWLER APPLICATION** ✓ From 200+ resources, crawl and serve news data on mobile phone, Mix news with twitter and facebook

✓ Apache Kafka for crawling data on demand, Ruby Sinatra Framework, Solr for

• Event Driven Design, Reactive Systems • Java 9/11 Experience, Kafka Streams / kSqlDb • Reactive Programming, Reactive Manifesto, Scalable Systems • Java 1.6, 1.7, 1.8, Functional Programming, Design Patterns experience (Advanced)

WORKFLOW ✓ Accept and Analyze Problem ✓ Find most suitable solution

• Dockerize Applications, CI/CD, Jenkins Integrated Applications

• Spring Data, Rest, Webflux, Oauth, Hibernate, JWT (Advanced)

• Scala for multithreaded processing with functional

• Scala for multithreaded processing with functional

• Redis Sentinel, Redis Server Cluster, Sharding

• Hazelcast Cluster, Google Guava, Ehcache

Clean code, Microservices Architectures

Spring Rest Docs, Mockito, JUnit

✓ Develop most efficiently

✓ Agile Development & Scrum

Java 1.8 New fetures (2015) (Oracle) # Java EE (2013-2014) - Oracle * Spring Framework Architecture (2013) (kodcu.com)

JavaSE and Design Patterns (2007) (Oracle)

* Oracle OCA Certificate (2011) (Oracle-Ireland)

GIVEN LECTURES ✓ Startup Roadmap (I.T.U Cekirdek)

✓ Reactive Programming (Turkcell Technology)

✓ Java 1.8 New features (Turkcell Technology)

EDUCATION

✓ Sql Tuning (Bilge Adam)

Graduated.

INTERESTS

SKILLS PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & TOOLS

Y (Mesaj.Ninja Project) BNP Paribas & TEB International Hackhaton Winner in ISTANBUL (2015)

• Ruby (Intermediate) - Sinatra, Rails Frameworks

• Apache Kafka Messaging (Pub/Sub)

AWARDS & CERTIFICATIONS

- **SELÇUK UNIVERSITY**

ENGINEERING FACULTY - COMPUTER ENGINEERING DEPARTMENT

• In my free time I like playing guitar, playing football, driving a car, and reading politics. • Professionally, I like to constantly develop myself, create other fields, learn other languages, produce new ideas and projects.

REFERENCES

• References will be supplied in case of request.